Tyler Duprey Web Developer

Tyler Duprey

Toronto Area

419.407.6652 tyler@tylerduprey.com

Skills

I'm a web developer who specializes in static websites as well as full stack JavaScript web applications. I'm also a marketer, copywriter and skilled designer. I am an expert in writing semantic HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Node.JS. I am familiar with MongoDB and React as well. I have extensive experience with the Adobe Creative Suite for both design and development.

Experience

TylerDuprey.Com / Teacher

May 2019 - PRESENT, Toronto Area

I build and maintain a personal website with daily content updates, an ecommerce system, and a beautiful design. I regularly produce video tutorials about web design that users watch through a custom video player I built.

Aktion Associates / Marketing Coordinator

Aug 2016 - Jun 2018, Toledo, OH Area

I Supported the development and implementation of tactical marketing communications projects, developed marketing campaigns that align to product strategies, and utilized marketing technology including email automation, CRM, and opportunity management systems. I managed Microsoft Dynamics CRM, provided analytics and success metrics for all campaigns. I also coordinated and executed marketing events such as trade shows and online webinars and created content for website, sales, social media, and email.

Large US Bank / Web Designer

Sept 2014 - Aug 2016, Columbus, OH

I maintained and improved the design and usability of internal web resources. I worked with a small team to manage a complex network of web files impacting multiple teams and departments. I wrote and edited HTML and CSS files using Adobe Dreamweaver. I balanced multiple tasks while working under tight deadlines.

Ohio History Connection / Online Content Specialist

Oct 2013 - Aug 2014, Columbus, OH

I supported OHS marketing goals by creating and curating content for the web. I worked with a content management systems (CMS) to design and develop landing pages for events, exhibits, educational programs and public information. I supported the marketing team with IT objectives. I created and acquired content for email newsletters and other online communications media. I supported internal communication, social media, and online content strategy plans. I worked with Google Analytics to report on web use.

Education

Ohio University / BS in Journalism, Public Relations

Aug 2007 - Jun 2012, Athens, OH

Activities and Societies: Public Relations Student Society of America (PRSSA), OU ImPRessions, Residential Housing, Cru, tRAC, Student Senate and College Republicans.